{"id":"2018_2","name":"","memoryVerse":"\"Have I not commanded you? Be strong and courageous. Do not be afraid; do not be discouraged, for the Lord your God will be with you wherever you go.\" â€“ Joshua 1:9","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.","questions":[{"id":"2018_2_1","questionText":"1. Use this space to record how you have seen God's activity during the week. (How has He provided, answered, comforted, reconciled, guided, etc.?)","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_2_2","questionText":"2. What from the notes, lecture, group sharing or personal study impacted you most in the past week?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read Joshua 5:13-6:27.","readVerse":[{"book":"Joshua","verse":"5:13-6:27"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_2_3","questionText":"3. Who did Joshua meet near Jericho? Why might he have replied to Joshua's questions as he did?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_2_4a","questionText":"4. a. How would the Lord's words have encouraged Joshua, considering the walls of Jericho were tightly shut? What do they tell us about God?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_2_4b","questionText":"4. b. What was unique or interesting about the battle strategy? What effect might it have had on the Israelites and the residents of Jericho?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_2_5a","questionText":"5. a. What did God command the Israelites to do to Jericho, and why? Whom were they to spare, and why? (For help, see Genesis 15:16; Deuteronomy 12:29-32; Deuteronomy 20:16-18; Leviticus 18:24-28.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Genesis","verse":"15:16"},{"book":"Deuteronomy","verse":"12:29-32"},{"book":"Deuteronomy","verse":"20:16-18"},{"book":"Leviticus","verse":"18:24-28"}]},{"id":"2018_2_5b","questionText":"5. b. Describe any struggle you may have to reconcile God's wrath against sin and His love for people.","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read Joshua 7.","readVerse":[{"book":"Joshua","verse":"7:1-999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_2_6","questionText":"6. What was Joshua's response to the battle of Ai? What does his prayer reveal about his knowledge of and relationship with God?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_2_7","questionText":"7. What did God reveal to Joshua? How did Achan respond when caught, and what resulted?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_2_8","questionText":"8. What consequences have you experienced because of wrongdoing (yours or others')?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read Joshua 8.","readVerse":[{"book":"Joshua","verse":"8:1-999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_2_9a","questionText":"9. a. What do you learn about God from His words to Joshua before the battle?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_2_9b","questionText":"9. b. How did God's battle plan differ from the spies' plan in 7:3?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_2_10","questionText":"10. Why did Joshua read God's words to the entire assembly after the battle at Ai? (See Deuteronomy 11:26-30 and 27:2-8 for Moses' instructions.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Deuteronomy","verse":"11:26-30"},{"book":"Deuteronomy","verse":"27:2-8"}]},{"id":"2018_2_11","questionText":"11. How can you share a love for and commitment to God's Word with your family and those around you?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read Joshua 9.","readVerse":[{"book":"Joshua","verse":"9:1-999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_2_12","questionText":"12. How did the surrounding nations respond to the Israelites' victories? What did this prompt the Gibeonites to do?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_2_13","questionText":"13. What should Joshua have done in response to the Gibeonites' request? Why did Joshua keep his promise to the Gibeonites? (See Exodus 34:12, 15; Numbers 30:2; Deuteronomy 7:2.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Exodus","verse":"34:12"},{"book":"Exodus","verse":"34:15"},{"book":"Numbers","verse":"30:2"},{"book":"Deuteronomy","verse":"7:2"}]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Review Joshua 5:13-9:27.","readVerse":[{"book":"Joshua","verse":"5:13-9:27"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_2_14","questionText":"14. Through this week's lesson, how is God moving you to engage with the world, share a truth or show His love and kindness?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]}}}